Ijas Nizamuddin
Associate Consultant - State Street

Irinchayam B.O, Kerala - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Ijas-Nizamuddin/6748d77f76f94eed

With close to 3 years of experience in IT industry, I have had excellent exposure to design,

development and implementation of Client Server Applications in various domains such as

Banking and Finance concepts. I have been involved in various software Development projects in Open System environment.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Associate Consultant

Oracle Corporation -

June 2011 to Present

State Street Global Advisors (SSgA) is the asset management business of State Street

Corporation, one of the world's leading providers of financial services to institutional investors1,

with a heritage dating back over two centuries. Backed by the strength and stability of the State

Street organization, SSgA makes continual investments in asset management and client service

platform, resulting in a client-focused, solutions-driven orientation . BrokerViews is the application

which list all the details about the counterparties who invest their securities in State Street. The

details also include ratings given by Bloomberg.

Responsibilities: Development, Testing and support. Software Used: Java, GWT

Associate Consultant

Oracle Corporation - Bangalore, Karnataka -

May 2010 to June 2011

This project is actually a redesign of an existing client website. The client website was designed

on Java Server Pages (JSP) and our aim was to change it into a more dynamic web page using

Adobe Flex. At first we changed the home page screen of the client website. After the successful

completion of that we incorporated flex in to the account section also. This data which is obtained

from DataBase is taken by the flex using a remote procedure call and the data is shown to the $\,$

user. With the use of Advanced Data Grids, Charts(including Bar and Pie Charts) the site increased

the readability and understandability of the users who were previously using the pages on java $\,$

server pages. This site developed by us won the IMC (Interactive Media Council)'s outstanding

achievement award in Financial information. The judge evaluate website based on 5 criteria:

Design, Content, Feature Functionality, Usability and Standard Compliance. Our website scored

475 out of a maximum of 500 points.

Responsibilities: Development, Testing and support.

Software Used: Java, Adobe Flex

https://www.indeed.com/r/Ijas-Nizamuddin/6748d77f76f94eed?isid=rex-download&ikw=download-top&co=IN

https://www.indeed.com/r/Ijas-Nizamuddin/6748d77f76f94eed?isid=rex-download&ikw=download-top&co=IN

Framework: Springs, MVC

Associate Consultant

Oracle Corporation - Bangalore, Karnataka -

February 2010 to April 2010

Description: Development of Basel II Application, Basel II is the second of the Basel Accords,

which are recommendations on banking laws and regulations issued by the Basel Committee on

Banking Supervision. The purpose of Basel II, which was initially published in June 2004, is to

create an international standard that banking regulators can use when creating regulations about $\ensuremath{\mathsf{S}}$

how much capital banks need to put aside to guard against the types of financial and operational

risks banks face. In practice, Basel II attempts to accomplish this by setting up rigorous risk

and capital management requirements designed to ensure that a bank holds capital reserves

appropriate to the risk the bank exposes itself to through its lending and investment practices.

The New Accord includes several methodologies for determining a bank's risk-based capital

(CU) and Stress Test (ST), the methodologies that will be used for repostyle transactions are

Simple VaR if the collateral is eligible. If the collateral is ineligible then the Wholesale loan

approach will be utilized or the collateral will be reduced to zero in the Simple VaR.

Roles and Responsibilities: Development, Testing and support. Software Used: Oracle 9i

OTHER PROJECTS AND REAL TIME TRAINING:

RTRM(Railway Ticketing System Through Mobile)

A mobile based real time application with many exciting features like checking pnr status, train availability, trains between stations etc. This application was done in j2me and it uses weblogic as server and MSSQL as the database.

Undergone a mandatory Training on Finance By Oracle Corporation

EDUCATION

Birla Institute Of Technology - Pilani, Rajasthan

2011

Bachelor of Technology in Computer Science

University College Of Engineering, University Of Kerala

2005 to 2009

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

SKILL SET:

Languages: Core Java

Front end/GUI Tools programming: Adobe Flex, GWT

Database: Oracle 10g

IDE: Eclipse, FlexBuilder

FrameWorks: Spring(Basics), MVC frame work Operating System: Windows, Linux, Unix